Speaker 1: so
Speaker 2: I decided this this car doesn't need to go win races it doesn't need to go compete against you know wealthy people with their vintage Formula One cars and their Indy cars it doesn't need to do that what it needs to be able to do is be a great platform for students to learn on and
Speaker 3: build and is low maintenance over long.
Speaker 3: period of time because this chassis is so cool. So, the choice was made to run the Honda K-Series. This is the K24, 2.4 liter four cylinder, readily available in a lot of production-based
Speaker 4: cars. And in the United States, this particular variant was the one that makes about the most horsepower. And there's a lot of parts available for it. So in turbocharged form, as you all know from the internet, the K-Series can make up to 1,000 horsepower, depending on how you do it.
Speaker 4: But in stock form
kind
Speaker 3: of unplugged they're gonna make about 200 horsepower also Grayson where yet come on over here You can keep working. You don't have to stop just cuz the camera's on I'm making him nervous This is his first time on camera. Oh, how do you feel? I feel good.
Speaker 5: You're talking quietly. I'm sorry Okay, so
Speaker 3: Grayson's local
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): he's a genius garage student and long story short guys I'm doing the machining on this to make the car be
a
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): actually usable in all the engineering. So it'll be rock solid for years to come for Genius Garage because the IndyCar will be here for doing engine building for the students. So they don't have to worry about the car. They can worry about building engines and tuning them. And if one blows up, it's
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): not the end all end of the world. But Grayson was local. So I said, why don't you come in a day a week and we'll work on it together. You can hang out and you can learn through the process and all that. So dude, this is like your third day here. - Yeah. - How are you
feeling
Speaker 8: it? - Good, I think it's going good. - Have you learned anything yet?
Speaker 9: - Yeah.
what
Speaker 9: have you learned a few different stuff a few structural stuff a little bit on the end of stuff i
mean uh
Speaker 9: quite a bit of fabrication so far so and
how weird it is
Speaker 10: to work with casey yeah
yeah i'm
Speaker 10: talking the third person it's not that bad it's kind of fun yeah the
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): people at the restaurant think we're
nuts yeah
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): because i'm a regular so uh what should we do with the rest of our day here should we show them the malarkey we're making
-
Speaker 11: Hmm, let's do your
Speaker 12: stuff. - Ooh,
Speaker 4: my stuff. So check this out. Now I know some of you are gonna say that stuff is too thick, but here's the K-Series, right? K-Series fits on this flat billet aluminum pan, which was originally designed by a student a couple of years ago, but there were a couple of mistakes made, so we had to redo it. But fortunately we were able to save the metal and make it work. You can see these two holes here, and that will be for the dry sump oiling system, and that's where the oil will be sucked for the pumps here.
Speaker 13: Now, don't worry about that now, we're worrying about structural stuff. - Yeah.
Speaker 13: the adapter plate that bolts to the billet the billet
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): oil pan as well as the motor at the bell housing flange and adapts it to the transaxle here the transaxle having these six bolts that are in the shape of a trapezoid on the back and then of course this top part called the toilet bolt of the transaxle has an area here where a plate can be bolted up at the top but for right now just keep your mind here we have the engine adapted to the transmission to where the input shaft will actually go into
Speaker 3: the flywheel for the clutch and make that all work.
Speaker 3: now the oil pan here that's billet goes over and fits over four
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): pins that come out of the
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): monocoque which is the big carbon fiber chassis here and the aluminum you can see the bulkhead is aluminum and those are the structural pins you can see those are the two at the top there's two over there and then there are four down there at the bottom they go into the billet oil pan and
Speaker 16: then from below you are able to tighten up the nuts that go on it so right now relating to the structure, as you
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): can see,
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): There's a point here, and there's a point here to the monocoque. The engine is only attached at the bottom and somewhat triangulated in this form for all you engineering types.
Speaker 17: So, we have made these pieces of steel here. You can see these two here that fit nicely right over that. Pretty tight tolerance, but not
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): psychotically tight. Goes over that with just a little bit of clearance so that then you can use these jet nuts and tighten them down. Now, the reason those are there is because...
We
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): need them to fit over where the car slides together. God,
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): can I not put a nut on a tape? There we go, okay, there. I'm good at some things, I swear.
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): Anyway, so what we're doing, this is visual. So here's the steel tubes, okay? And they're gonna get welded to structure that goes from here to here, okay? Now I know there's a triangulation coming up, so I want you guys to pay attention. Here's DOM tubing, got a little surface rust on it, but we're just using this as a visual representation.
So
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): effectively, we need tubing to go from this area and we have to decide how we're going to weld and take about all that and how we're going to make it attached here. But effectively, there's going to be a top tube from the monocoque to the
Speaker 17: back. Now, the other thing we're going to do is there's going to be a tube that goes from approximately this point down to here. Now I'm
going
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): to use this. This is not the one we're using. Obviously, I'm using this as a visual reference. So something
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): will weld to that tube and it will go to a point down low. So what we're going to end up doing is marking the
building
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): it here and when
this comes
Speaker 4: off we're gonna put it in the drill press and it's gonna get a hole drilled here because we have these which are two bends okay and this is 1/2 by 20 inch
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): thread and in a tube there'll be a hole drilled to where that'll bolt through to it like that and there will be a tube that goes on to the end of this that sticks out to about where my ring finger is here
and
Speaker 14 (lower-pitched voice): and welded to this obviously and that will allow another tube to be fish mouth and weld to it right there so what we have effectively done is make these a arms uh that all bolt together and then when the car is dismantled what you'll do is you'll unbolt the four nuts at the top and the four nuts
Speaker 3: at the bottom and the monocoque chassis here as well as the entire drive chain area with the wing the engine the transax and all that and the a arms will split here will split the car in and it will slide
Speaker 19 (lower-pitched voice): apart.
Speaker 19 (lower-pitched voice): you have to have your electrolyte fuel oil cooling lines and all that disconnected but that's how that's gonna
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): work so that's what we're working on right now and making these pieces here and I want to show you how I'm doing that because we had to go gorilla style I'm just gonna keep rolling with it like this and then Grayson's gonna hold it
Speaker 20: we don't have a lathe here I don't have any machine tools and frankly we don't have enough room for it we don't really use them that often however the difficulty is we need these parts now but we need them to
work
And
Speaker 20: the tube that we have been using to make
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): these, the problem was the ID of it was not big enough to just go over top of those things. And obviously you can see the flashing there where I cut it. The other problem is cutting this
Speaker 2: perfectly perpendicularly. If we had a lathe, it'd be very easy to put this in a lathe, spin it, cut it off perfectly where you need it to be, and then open up the inside with a boring, a center board kind of thing there. We don't have that. What
we
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): do have is a cutoff wheel. So as you can see, it was cut off.
But
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): even if you get it in there as perfectly perpendicular as you can, it will be slightly off. So one problem we have that has to be relieved is how do we make that perpendicular? What can we do? Can we put it in the drill press and spin it? No, it's too big. Can we hold it? Can we do it by hand? No. The other problem is the center has to be drilled out
Speaker 21: more. Fortunately, I've got a drill bit that works perfectly to do so. So what we're going
Speaker 16: to and then I set this up with the belt sander, which looks completely ridiculous.
But
Speaker 16: together here, I'm gonna show you guys how we made
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): this. So, if I may, I'm gonna give you this. And you're gonna record, but don't push any buttons. Is it still recording? Okay,
Speaker 22: you got it. So, got the piece here, you guys. I'm looking for safety glasses. Grayson, you see any around
here? Hmm,
Speaker 23: here
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): we go. Eye protection is important. Like, people way overdo it, but it's important. So come on
Speaker 24: over.
Speaker 25: Now, I'm gonna show you guys. First, we
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): gotta bore out the center
better.
I'm
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): going to take the piece and right here on this nice machinist vise there's a little groove cut into it. So I'm going to find the groove and tighten it up, but not before I've got to get some of this flashing off. So I'm going to just buzz the flashing off quick
on the coarse side. One, I don't want to
Speaker 26: cut myself, and two, if
there's flashing of
Speaker 26: about any thickness poking out.
Speaker 26: it may...
Speaker 27: it'll get in the way of having it
Speaker 28: perfect, you know, in the groove and set up and as straight as
I can get it.
Speaker 28: Okay.
Speaker 29: Alright. Find its groove. Okay,
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): that's in there. That's pretty nice. Now, we've got that. Here's my bit I'm using. Now, since we're only going to be taking a little bit off the center, a drill bit has a tendency to grab too quickly. So,
you
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): got to go a constant rate and get your speed the right way I've got this adjusted relatively slow but not as slow as it can go I'm gonna
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): use WD-40 a little bit as a coolant but also as a lubricant it's a little messy but it does it is in fact working well okay
Speaker 30: so safety glasses are on everything's like that it's gonna work just
fine I'm
Speaker 31: gonna spray just a little in there a little on the bed and we're
gonna start
I'm going to put
Speaker 32: my hip right here. I know this looks terrible. Don't be like that. What are you doing? There we go. But
it's getting a little
Speaker 33: dull. God damn it. So yeah...
Speaker 33: I pushed I just
Speaker 30: slipped and pushed a little too hard and it bound and grabbed it's a little tricky to do also I'm doing it on the camera and this looks 10 times more sketch so judge me if you will but it's working beautifully and we're doing the best with we can with what we got
and in a second when I get this
Speaker 34: done I'm going to tell you guys a lesson about doing the best you can with what you got I swear
it won't be a boomer lesson but
Speaker 35: it might sound
Speaker 36: like one
Speaker 36: And honestly, there's nothing wrong with the boomer lesson, just if it's good now and then.
Okay, it's bored
Speaker 37: out.
Speaker 38: Okay, so the lesson time. Do the best you can with what you got.
Speaker 38: And if you don't have specifically the exact tool you need, like a lathe would be nice, we
Speaker 22: don't have one. So I have to think about how can I do this at a 90-grade angle? How can I do a good enough job? Honestly, this drill bit, I don't know where the heck it came from. It's some old piece of junk I've had forever, but it happens to be the exact size I needed, and I found
it in a
Speaker 39: pile. So I bring that up because,
and this is also my
Speaker 39: way of getting back to stupid people,
which
Speaker 21: sometimes you need to
do in life.
Speaker 21: People who don't want to try hard, they don't want to work and they don't believe they can ever get anywhere, like
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): to see anybody else who has any modicum of success and write off their success to have say it was handed to them. Because if the person that was successful was known that they actually came up with some brilliant way and worked hard and tried and got somewhere, then that would make the people who didn't try feel worse about themselves. So that's why people
Speaker 3: like to do that. But I bring that up because finding clever ways to do this
It's
Speaker 3: just one small token of everything. So you guys may not be able to afford something great. You may not have the right
tool, you
Speaker 3: know, but if you think and use your hand, you have some good old fashioned blue collar trades, you
know,
Speaker 22: workmanship, then you might be able to do something special. Work on
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): something, fix up an old Lamborghini,
or
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): take an old Indy car and fix it up so here's what we got here's our part I put it in the water because it
was a
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): little hot to
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): touch now what I'm going to do is see did the boring work will this fit on there
now sure did
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): and with and I'm going by eyeball feel just enough just enough clearance to be perfect now you'll notice that this is longer than the shoulder it needs to be longer so that the nut will bottom out and push this into the bulkhead before it bottoms out on this pin
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): So now what we need to do is, this is not perfectly
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): perpendicular. I'm going to show you guys what I created to make this work. So I got my, this is my sander here. I've got the disc. This is a nice, flat, perfect plane.
Speaker 17: And this is parallel to it. So what I did is I took this 3 quarter inch square steel tubing and I clamped it to the edge of this.
Speaker 17: perfectly on the edge then i took my 90 degree magnet here and this piece of steel check this out guys fits in that magnet perfectly so i know now based on this being a 90 degree angle and this being perfectly parallel to
Speaker 3: this that this if i hold it here will buzz it perfectly straight now what i'm going to do is i want to show you guys this look at the coloration here you can see some discoloration you can see how it is
cut
Speaker 3: off
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): wheel right there same thing with here now what i'm going to do is i'm going to initially just touch this a little bit to it and also i'm going to check the screen to make sure this is
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): working yes it is so guys i'm going to start with this
just a
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): little bit and do half the job and then show it to you so you can
see how it was uneven here we go
Okay, now take a look
Speaker 40: here. You'll be able to see it. You can see that this area at the top has been buzzed,
Speaker 41: and that has not. This area was low, that was clearly a high spot. So I'm gonna keep going a little bit. Now, because this is perpendicular, it does not matter
Speaker 42: how this orients. It's still gonna get it perpendicular. So all I have to do is stick it back in here and slide it back up.
The other thing is if you
Speaker 42: come around here,
Speaker 43 (higher-pitched voice): come over here, cameraman.
Speaker 42: You can
Speaker 43 (higher-pitched voice): see the sparks going all the way around Well that helps let me know is it touching the whole way or is it just doing one corner? You can see the full width of sparks so that tells me Now you
can see
Speaker 43 (higher-pitched voice): it's shiny the whole way
Speaker 41: that tells me that I've now gotten this
Speaker 44: perfectly perpendicular and flat so
Speaker 45: what I'm gonna do I'm
just gonna put it
Speaker 44: in the water to cool it down because if I go touching it I'll burn myself and
Speaker 30: I want to burn myself and
I also wanna
Speaker 30: take off the least amount of material 'cause if I take off too much I'll ruin this because it'll
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): no longer be long enough that the bolt will bottom out on it first. But you can see that still fits on real nice. And now it'll have a perfectly perpendicular place for this jet nut to bottom out.
Speaker 46: But just for the eyeball test, I'm gonna flip it around, I'm gonna check it on the monocoque here.
Speaker 47: I'm gonna come over to the other side so I can see if there's any gap. I'm gonna
spin it.
And I can tell
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): you that there's no gap, and that is flawlessly perpendicular. And I was able to do it with no lathe. Now, this is not a whole lot different. When
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): you put it in there and spin it, it's kind of like if you're lapping valves. You put 'em in there and spin it if it's off a little bit. So it's just, this is just basic, good old-fashioned
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): ingenuity.
And I
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): guarantee any good fabricator that isn't a jillionaire with a big shop or farmer has had to do clever stuff like this in the past. All
Speaker 34: right.
Speaker 34: I'll tell you one other lesson after this in a moment. I'm going to go ahead and hit this. I'm going to show you how we did it.
All right, I buzzed it just a
Speaker 30: little. You can see that this half was hit. That's the high spot. So now I got to keep going until it hits
Speaker 48: the low spot as well. Here we go.
Speaker 41: Excellent.
Speaker 41: Take a look here. You can see that it buzzed it the whole way around and that's perpendicular. So we're gonna take it over to the car. I'm gonna check it. Oop,
a bunch of junk
Speaker 49: came out. That's all right. Looks
Speaker 21: good. All right, so what I'm gonna do is come over here guys and I'm gonna hit the edge. I'm just gonna do this by hand. Push the magnet out of the way a little bit. Just gonna hold it at
Speaker 50: an angle. Spin
it.
it's not
Speaker 50: imperative that this is flawlessly chamfered but I can do a good enough
job all righty where's
Speaker 51: that
Speaker 46: towel
So that's how you did
Speaker 46: it, guys. We don't have a lathe, and we don't have all the right tools, and we didn't have a pipe that fit perfectly, but with just the basic
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): things we have and using our head, we were able to make this part fit perfectly. It's nicely
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): perpendicular, nicely chamfered, and now we have something worthy of using on this incredible Indy car.
we
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): hand fit these and we have four tubes for every single one so that gets us in a great place now i want to bring something up about this too i
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): said that any person with their own garage fabrication any farmer gets it so some of you may know the family business when i grew up was a little public golf course in ohio it's now defunct because 2008 destroyed
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): the industry but that's neither here nor
We
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): worked hard. Our family had to maintain every single mower, every single tractor, every single golf cart, all the grounds, all the agronomy, 120 acres, all the environmental impact, and then also manage the business. But the only thing that people
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): saw on the outside were wearing a polo shirt and khakis if there was a golf thing going on or the front side of it.
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): I was just the rich kid, even though we were the ones responsible firsthand of maintaining an entire fleet of internal combustion and electric vehicles
Speaker 19 (lower-pitched voice): and maintaining 120 acres. So I bring that up also because never write somebody off for being successful. They may have to use a lot of ingenuity to get themselves there. And just think about all the farmers working hard and having to
Speaker 52: maintain and repair their equipment. It's not glamorous, but there's a lot of smarts going on there that we all need. So I just wanted to
say
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): that. Anyway, I got this part made. So let's talk We'll talk about some other things going
on
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): back to it
and we're
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): about ready to make the structure so you can
Speaker 53: see right here this plate this is on the k-series that's where the water pump was but it was this big ugly water pump and that gets away in the structure we're going to we're going to use this tube as a visual aid
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): we may use a smaller tube in diameter but works so that goes in there but it's starting to hit the manifold now we notice the stock manifold how it comes up and wraps around
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): actually works perfectly it's going to fit over this tube real nicely and don't forget that we're still going to going to have one triangulating coming in down here.
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): Okay.
But
Speaker 53: for right now, what we have to do is make the corners. These are the important spots right here that have to bolt together. So we have to make these, we have to make the parts down here. We're going to have to take this
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): plate off and drill it. And then later when we get the plate, we're going to have to make this. And when we have all three of these corners on both sides, these tubes that bolt onto the pins, this plate that goes here, and then also the tube end with the tube and the bolt drilled,
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): when we have all those things that can be bolted down solidly then we can take whatever tubes we're going to use and start connecting the dots and then tack weld them and
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): weld them nicely both on the car and off and then we will have made our a-arms which will be perfect and that's how you build the structure but and that's what's been holding this car back for so long and the reason why i wanted to work on it so that you know genius garage has the lotus exosphere has the daytona prototype and the old yellow corvette up here which has been great and helped with a lot of jobs and such
They
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): all teach different things, they're all helpful, we can go race them, but I know that lots of students have wanted to build engines, but the problem with engine building is it's a massive curriculum on its own. You can easily get a four-year degree and then a master's and doctorate on engine building. So to think that students can learn everything they need to know about engine building in a couple months is crazy. But it doesn't mean that...
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): it wouldn't be a cool thing if we can give them an opportunity to start to learn. So the Honda K series is a great place to start and this is a really great platform for it. And since we have the Exosphere, which is an open-wheel fast car, it can suit the job of maintaining something high end and understanding how to tune something really amazing like that for the part of learning in the jobs. And then this one doesn't have to worry about having that job. So we have this motor, which stock makes 200 horsepower and is on gasoline, but this platform was designed for for 800 horsepower burning methanol.
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): which runs cooler. But still,
Speaker 16: the cooling system is far more than adequate for what the K-series can do. The gearbox, the brakes, everything about it is far, far, far overkill
Speaker 4: for what this motor can do. So the exciting part about that
Speaker 38: is, this is our first one. Let's run this naturally aspirated. It's gonna be a backup. We can get the whole car built and tuning and all that jazz. But then the next thing we can do is we can find another motor,
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): identical, used one, and then the students can start building that.
And
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): then all the work that both myself to get it started and other students do in terms of creating a first step of it, then that can translate to the next motor that they get to build and learn the lessons on and figure it out in an environment. Now, we're not going to build it to blow it up, but if it were to blow up, you don't have as massive amount of money invested, at least in the basis, you know, parts started to get expensive, but far less money than something else when a motor like this may only cost $800 to $1,000 in total. So that's why I'm making the effort and really making
this
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): overkill because i want them to have an opportunity to build an engine and learn that i think that's really neat and i'm excited that this car it's a very exciting car for gina's garage to have is something that can be valuable again
so the
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): last thing i'll
Speaker 3: tell you guys is uh as you'll notice it's in the back come on over here and we can just look around
Speaker 3: So the back here is where I do most
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): of my stuff and also do a lot of YouTube. And frankly, I'll be honest, the only reason Genius Garage can exist anymore is because I do my own YouTube and give it exposure. The world is not remotely as nice as everybody thinks it is, which is amazing, 'cause I think most people think the world is terrible. It's very difficult for
a
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): nonprofit to exist. Well, I don't charge any students to be here. So fortunately, I'm able to give that exposure and make it work. And come walk with me. Don't die, don't trip and dry, Gray. Thanks for grabbing the camera.
You
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): know, Gina's garage up front has a fair amount of room
as you can
Speaker 54: see
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): here with the cars, but we had to bring the IndyCar with the table in the back where
Speaker 3: there's more room. So that here we can finish the Daytona prototype, we can keep working on the Exosphere. You got the carts and the sprint car up there. I had to jam the Zero up here for now 'cause that's my workspace in the back. So it's just kind of the relationship there. Maybe someday someone or some corporation will support millions of dollars so Gina's garage can have its own stuff.
Speaker 3: until
Speaker 38: that time i'm going to donate you know my spot and tools and things to be
Speaker 53: able to work on it and so we have this great work area and with grayson making this be something so it can be utilized for the students for engine building and such in the future you
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): guys can see here we've got a cool turbo i'm gonna fall and die we've got a turbo and if you want to see about where that's going to go come
on over here
And
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): this is pretty neat. So it's gonna get mounted right about here, which is in the back of the side pod, above the Venturi. And the tubes,
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): we have stainless steel tube coming, which we're gonna take and mock up, which will go right there into the turbo. And then this is where the exhaust will come out. You can see the,
Speaker 55: ooh, turbo blades, yay.
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): But anyway, it'll get mounted like right about here.
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): and then it'll be a straight three-inch pipe out the back that go like straight out the back that's cool and of course you got your uh your wastegate external wastegate which will blow it in there if you need but then here's the intake which we're going to probably
Speaker 17: run and have a filter up here because there's two scoops where to get dead cool air and then we'll clock this so that this tube will come and run through here and this is where the original turbo was in the bell housing the indycar
Speaker 17: We're going to do it like that. There's a bunch of constraints, but what we are going to do is put
Speaker 16: inside there a water to air intercooler to cool it. So what's really cool is the entire length of the charge, the pressure side of the intake will only
Speaker 20: go right through here. You have your air water intercooler and it'll come over there to the intake side. I'm going to show you what we're thinking
there.
Speaker 25: We're going to modify the stock intake, which is pretty
neat, really.
so
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): here's the second half of the stock intake and we're going to get rid of all that stuff with the cooling going through it and whatnot we're going to cut off this flange and we're going to another flange and we're going to weld it on straight so your throttle your butterfly will be here will be mechanical throttle and it'll tube will just go right through there so it's only going to be this long so you're not going to have all these miles and miles of cockamamie tubing so you'll be able to reduce lag quite a bit but be able to cool it
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): and with the we have a big water radiator here we also have two others that can make it so it's only half a water radiator and the other side could in fact just be for the the water from the intercooler or what we may try is this is a very nice cnr radiator this alone this radiator alone is potentially enough to cool this whole motor up to like 400 or 500 horsepower so if all the cooling of the
If the
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): motor is on the left side, then that means we can leave this radiator for cooling the intercooler
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): and then we have an air to oil cooler here for the motor. So if this ends up being more than enough radiator for the intercooler, which it probably will be, but if everything else is, if the oil is cooling fine and the coolant is cooling fine, then that's fine if it over cools, we can always block some of it off.
Speaker 56 (lower-pitched voice): we could also if need be if it over cools the intercooler and we've got extra cooling capacity we could run an inline water to oil heat exchanger to
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): utilize some of the cooling effect of the water for oil if need be but we also have the ability to change out the left side to be half and half so we could make half of one side for cooling
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): the intercooler over there which might make sense because there's you know stuff we got room in the side pot over there and then And then we can use
this
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): for the engine water radiator and then half of that for it as well so that can also work so that'll be a fun experimentation with the students in the future and getting data but that's
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): what I'm working on guys yeah and come on over here and look this way if you don't mind I'd frankly love it if the
Speaker 57: students were able to just do all this and have all the experiences but I'm gonna be honest and I hope you guys
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): understand this after a decade of working with college students
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): in engineering and high-end stuff,
and I
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): mean this in the nicest way possible, college students have only had so much life experience, fabrication experience and experience with tools. And a lot of the things here are frankly well beyond even the most talented and smartest college student on the planet's expertise. So that's where I have to jump in and help them or frankly do some of this
work
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): So it will be up to a standard that the things that they do and learn, they'll be able to make it go. Because, you know, one sad thing about YouTube is a lot of the builds
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): you guys see on YouTube that look really cool on the screen are garbage. They're garbage cars, they're not going to handle, they're not going to drive, they're not going to do anything.
And I
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): built cars and race cars
in the
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): real world before I ever
Speaker 19 (lower-pitched voice): did YouTube.
Speaker 19 (lower-pitched voice): for genus garage i want the students to have the experience to where they're actually working toward a bar of something working in the real world and that's why they end up getting amazing jobs from hr people and ceos of fortune 500 companies and manufacturers because they know that this isn't just
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): youtube bs this is real high level stuff and also in building an organization like genus garage even though we have
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): modest means by in terms of being a big educational organization and mostly it falls on my shoulders of time i don't mind making that sacrifice but i do want genus garage to continue to grow and be something worthwhile so creating this car into something that can teach
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): with motor building in an exciting and safe way while they're also learning about you know high level stuff i think that's the best we can possibly do as a side note regarding youtube i'm excited to see if rob dom finishes indy car and how that goes i believe he also has a champ car of
a similar era
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): looks like he's got a nice engine for it the original but it does appear that his rolling chassis
not in the
Speaker 58: best condition so I think
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): he's gonna have a lot of work there but I'm excited and hope that he finishes that one day and who knows maybe we'll get to do something together but you know genius garage got our own things to do so that's the video guys I hope you've enjoyed it I'm kind of being a little more chill in real world I just I'm frankly really just over the theatrics of YouTube
and
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): stuff and I just want to be real and be honest and hopefully that's the most helpful thing to everybody and if people don't like real and honesty well then maybe they're there for the wrong reasons and I don't want to feed into that but I hope you guys learned something and enjoyed this and even if you didn't I guess it doesn't matter because I'll get to teach and help people get jobs with that and that's the whole reason I ended up on BenWiki and here in the first place is to try to help Genus Garage grow. See
you guys next
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): time.